MANZUR A. SHAHEED

Springfield, NJ 07081, USA Cell: +1 646 895 0567

Email:shaheed_manzur@yahoo.com

PROFILE

Network Site Reliability Engineer (SRE). Extensive experience in planning, deploying and managing IT Infrastructure projects and in designing technical architecture for data communications networks. Have specific technical skills in data communications planning, network management systems and data network security. Strength in managing technical resources and alignment of information technology to business objectives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Managing IT Projects scoping, planning, budgeting, implementing, and staff management.
- Design and Implementation of Layer 2 Local Area Networks (LAN), optimum performance configuration, identify bottlenecks and implement cost-effective solution.
- Layer 3 and Wide Area Networks (WAN) Requirement analysis, design and implementation. Routing Protocols (BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, RIP), Router configuration, Layer 3 Switching, QoS, Firewalls (Checkpoint, Palo Alto), IPSec and MPLS VPNs, Network Management and monitoring.
- Network Services DNS, DHCP, TFTP, NTP, Syslog etc.
- Internet/Intranet based solutions development configuration, administration, reporting and maintenance of web servers.
- Advanced Programming (Python, PHP, Shell Scripts, Perl, C, Javascript, MySql, Ansible) and version control using Github, plan and track development projects with Jira.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2007 - Current

Bloomberg L.P, USA, http://www.bloomberg.com/

An information-services, news and media company that provides business and financial professionals with the tools and data on a single all-inclusive platform.

Network Site Reliability Engineer (Engineering Team)

- Develop Python programs for proactively monitoring of network configuration mismatches and overall network health.
- Develop Ansible playbooks for configuration deployment and stats collection.
- Manage Bloomberg Financial Network provide level3 support, identify issues and resolve them, escalate to Network Design group.
- Manage network inventory, maintain relationship with vendors and manage yearly maintenance contract renewals and true-ups.
- Maintain Network repository and produce various network deployment reports.
- Hardware refresh infrastructure work for various node sites design, produce BoM, obtain quote, procurement, configuration, installation, documentation and hand over to Operations.

Network & System Engineer (Market Data Team)

Award: 2011 Bloomberg Operations Award - Most Valuable Player (MVP) of the year. *Responsibilities:*

- Supported and implemented Market Data Feeds, Exchanges, Enterprise Services, and Market Data Infrastructure. Managed Bloomberg financial feed network and various data feed from stock exchanges to trading systems and electronic trading platforms.
- Performed installation/management of Bloomberg appliances (Linux based) at customer sites. Worked closely with application developers for these appliances to package and roll-out software on these appliances.
- Actively participated in MPLS from Frame Relay and data center migration projects.

May 2005 - Jan 2007

Telstra Corporation, Melbourne, Australia, http://www.telstra.com/

Telstra is a leading Australian Telecommunications and Managed Services provider Company. Network Designer (Contract position)

Projects Completed:

- Completed a project to design a network for Business Process Outsourcing to an off-shore vendor. Design
 includes Routing/Switching, Firewall rules, IPSec Tunnel, BGP, Global Site Selector (GSS), Content Service
 Switches (CSS) and DNS.
- Completed network design for multiple projects of various complexities including BGP, EIGRP, MPLS VPN, IPSec tunnel, redundancy and resiliency, Firewall rules and server load balancing.

 Network design for segregation of a business unit of National Australia Bank that was sold to a different company.

Senior Network Specialist (Contract position)

Sensis Pty Ltd, Melbourne, Australia, http://www.about.sensis.com.au/

Sensis is an Australian Advertising and Search Company comprises of WhitePages, YellowPages, CitySearch, WhereIS and many more (Sensis is owned by Telstra Corporation).

Projects Completed:

- Upgrade of Sensis Online Network infrastructure before Commonwealth Games 2006.
- Completed network design for multiple projects involving redundancy and resiliency, multiple firewalled VLANs, Load Balancers, SSL Accelerators and Caches.
- Migrated exiting services from legacy network to Gigabits network with minimal or no service disruption.
- Setup a nine level new office network with IPMAN services, dual core redundant network, firewalled VLANs, Voice over IP (VoIP), Wireless and Audio Visual Systems.

April 2000 - March 2005

IT Consultant (Contract position)

Australia Post, Australia, http://www.auspost.com.au/

Projects Completed:

FuturePost - network consists of 12 sites Australia wide with Cisco Catalyst switches and Cisco routers. The IT systems for Mail Processing Equipment (MPE) are Unix and WinTel based.

- FuturePost Network Upgrade implement fully switched network, standardise switch and router operating
 systems revisions, standardise network settings for IT systems. Detailed documentation, diagrams and
 inventory of all sites, provide redundancy in terms of spare parts to all sites.
- MPE Time synchronisation developed Technical Architecture for MPE time synchronisation and managed its
 rollout.
- Network Management installation and configuration of CiscoWorks 2000, deployment of Cisco Switch Probes, developed software to display network statistics (utilization and error) and report on network using Perl, JavaScript and HTML.
- Design and Implement Remote Access for Vendors using dial-up and VPN through the Corporate firewall.
 Implement Access Control at each MPE site.

Parcel Delivery Data - a project to increase the parcel tracking information captured with Symbol handheld barcode scanners.

- Design and supervise the implementation of the network including VPN and Firewall.
- Test scanner against IP connectivity, DNS, Radius and Firewall.
- Network acceptance and performance test.
- Manage setup DHCP at different delivery centres.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

- M.S (Computer Science), Asian Institute of Technology (AIT), Bangkok, Thailand.
- B.S (Computer System Engineering), Odessa Polytechnic Institute (OPI), Odessa, Ukraine.
- Cisco Certified Security Professional (CCSP), 2004, 2009.
- Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP), 2000, 2009, 2012, 2015, 2018.
- Juniper Networks Certified Associate (JNCIA), 2013.2018
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), 2011.